<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on steves ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.stevem.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on steves ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 17:21:56 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stevem.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>installing sentry on ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/quick-start-installing-sentry-on-ubuntu-14-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 17:21:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/quick-start-installing-sentry-on-ubuntu-14-04/</guid>
      <description>Intro So you want to deploy Sentry in your local environment, eh? Assuming you already know what Sentry does, I&amp;rsquo;ll just give you the tagline from their website: Sentry provides real-time crash reporting for your web apps, mobile apps, and games. That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fantastic summary. What I use it for is gathering, grouping, and alerting on Ruby on Rails application issues. It wraps errors up in to a nice, easy to digest package that you can work through, resolve, and get trend analysis on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>issues resolving .local dns in ubuntu 15.04</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/issues-resolving-local-dns-in-ubuntu-15-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 14:25:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/issues-resolving-local-dns-in-ubuntu-15-04/</guid>
      <description>The problem After getting my Ubuntu 15.04 desktop setup I noticed Chrome/Firefox was unable to properly resolve my local domain (*.home.local).
For example, when trying to view the vCenter web interface at https://vc.home.local, or trying to SSH into my PostgreSQL development box postgres-dev-01.home.local I&amp;rsquo;d just get ssh: Could not resolve hostname exit: Temporary failure in name resolution. This was made especially odd since an nslookup was able to resolve everything just fine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>disable gzip compression in fog</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/disable-gzip-compression-in-fog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 13:26:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/disable-gzip-compression-in-fog/</guid>
      <description>This was originally posted on my old blog back in 2010ish, restored it here for archival purposes.
Recently I changed the software the imaging server at work uses from Clonezilla to FOG. There were many reasons for the change such as a better web interface, image deployment queue, etc however one of the main things I was looking forward to was storage nodes which allows for distribution of images across multiple servers to extend storage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
