<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on steves ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on steves ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 22:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stevem.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>homelab management with labman</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/homelab-management-with-labman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 22:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/homelab-management-with-labman/</guid>
      <description>Recently I decided to try and throw together a one stop shop for managing frequently performed actions in my homelab. The goal was to enable me to faster create VMs, test software, rip them down, and rebuild. This is where I started with LabMan - HomeLab Manager.
It is very alpha. Very very alpha. It consists of 2 components: a Rails application that handles background jobs and the web UI, and an agent written in Go that runs on the servers and checks them in while providing some general info such as installed packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>haproxy in the homelab</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/hits-haproxy-web-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 22:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/hits-haproxy-web-interface/</guid>
      <description>HAProxy is my homelab loadbalancer of choice due to it&amp;rsquo;s versatility and general ease of configuration. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s HTTP or just plan TCP traffic I want to land within my lab, a few tweaks to an HAProxy config is all it takes. However, as I deploy more and more random services, which I want available from the internet, having to remote into my various HAProxy ingress servers becomes a pain. Also, since I like to have isolated HAProxy instances depending on what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, yet again having to remote into boxes to make changes becomes even more tiresome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using rails 5 and paperclip s3 with minio</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/paperclip-s3-minio-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/paperclip-s3-minio-rails/</guid>
      <description>Odds are if you&amp;rsquo;ve landed here you&amp;rsquo;re aware of what Paperclip is and the purpose it servces within a Rails application. If not, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a gem that will handle file uploads. In my case I use it for resizing images, saving them somewhere (S3), then easily presenting them back to the user inside of a view.
Note: This tutorial should work with any S3 compatible object storage API. Minio is just one of the more common ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>collecting bind dns stats with sensu</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/collecting-bind-dns-stats-with-sensu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 22:14:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/collecting-bind-dns-stats-with-sensu/</guid>
      <description>Recently I migrated off of AWS Route53 to my own BIND servers for a few of my domains. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do this because I think I can do DNS better than the folks at Amazon. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m looking to collect some detailed statistics about DNS usage and running my own DNS servers was the path of least resistance to reach that goal.
Prepping the DNS servers My DNS setup is fairly typical, with a master and slave DNS server, each one located on different sides of the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getting started with openshift v3 on vmware</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/getting-started-with-openshift-v3-on-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 07:23:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/getting-started-with-openshift-v3-on-vmware/</guid>
      <description>Goal After following this tutorial you should end up with a functional environment running OpenShift Origin. This environment will consist of 1 Master and 4 Nodes which isn&amp;rsquo;t a fully production-ready environment as ideally you will have multiple masters. We will be taking advantage of the OpenShift Ansible repository to tackle a majority of the heavy lifting, thus most of these steps fit into the &amp;ldquo;prep work&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;testing that everything worked as planned&amp;rdquo; category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to download Veeam Backup &amp; Replication 9.5 update 1</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/download-veeam-backup-and-recovery-9-5-update-1-rc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 11:40:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/download-veeam-backup-and-recovery-9-5-update-1-rc/</guid>
      <description>The general process for getting an early release of Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication 9.5 Update 1, which adds support for vCenter 6.5, is making a support ticket with Veeam asking for the RC.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through that hassle you can just download it directly here: https://download2.veeam.com/veeam_backup_9.5.0.802.update1.RC.zip
Usual disclaimer applies: is not official release software etc. etc. etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do ASA Hairpinning with multiple Inside networks</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/hairpin-asa-multiple-inside-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 11:54:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/hairpin-asa-multiple-inside-networks/</guid>
      <description>The issue When trying to consume a service hosted inside your network via it&amp;rsquo;s external IP address, which is also the outside address of your Cisco ASA, your connection will time out.
Given the network diagram above we want to achieve the following:
 openshift-builder (10.8.3.253) needs to pull down code from git server gogs.stevem.io (107.189.44.118) &amp;ndash; which according to our diagram has an internal IP of 10.8.1.254 Outside interface has 107.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HomeLab Revision 2016.12</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/homelab-end-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 23:52:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/homelab-end-2016/</guid>
      <description>Current network diagram You can view the current HomeLab diagram here: 
For those who have never seen this before: yes, I did run fiber out to my shed. I live in Minnesota and last winter I took advantage of the ridiculously cold winters we have and housed some servers out there.
Major changes Here is a list of big changes made in the current revision:
 Dedicated pfSense firewall was replaced with virtual Cisco ASAv firewall Replacing the firewall means I&amp;rsquo;m connecting my cable modem to my Cisco 3750 core switch Also replaced the virtual pfSense firewall on my dedicated server in Atlanta with a pair of active/standby ASAv firewalls Upgraded host-to-storage networking to 10Gb which included adding 3x10Gb interfaces to my FreeNAS box Moved from NFS to iSCSI for VMware datastore share in order to achieve a network configuration where I can direct connect ESXi hosts to FreeNAS while still having a single common datastore (with working vmotions, DRS, etc) Added an HP DL380 G7 to the lab (2x Xeon L5630, 96GB RAM, 4x 300GB 10k drives) Started migrating hosted projects from Kubernetes to OpenShift Origin  Wish list Of course these additions sparked some additions to my wish list:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing ASDM Login Error on Cisco ASA and ASAv</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/fixing-asdm-cisco-asa-and-asav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 11:03:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/fixing-asdm-cisco-asa-and-asav/</guid>
      <description>The problem &amp;ndash; ASDM Won&amp;rsquo;t launch properly When setting up a Cisco ASA Virtual Appliance (ASAv) in my lab I ran into issues getting ASDM to launch properly. When attempting to login I&amp;rsquo;d be prompted with the message &amp;ldquo;Unable to launch device manager from X.X.X.X&amp;rdquo; as seen in the screenshot below:
The logs indicate it&amp;rsquo;s an error with how SSL is configured on the ASA:
Application Logging Started at Thu Dec 15 15:51:05 CST 2016 --------------------------------------------- Local Launcher Version = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moving to hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 23:44:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Custom beginnings Back in 2014 I wrote a simple blog CMS in Ruby on Rails. It didn&amp;rsquo;t have the most features in the world but did have all the functionality I needed at the time, which included:
 Uploading images to AWS S3 and storing multiple sizes Visual editor for the Admin area Post tagging Syntax highlighting Comment system  It was pretty barebones but worked well enough. There was one major &amp;ldquo;shortcoming&amp;rdquo;, and that was the reliance on a database for storing posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>containers in production</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/containers-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 07:42:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/containers-in-production/</guid>
      <description>Quick background My job involves doing &amp;ldquo;DevOpsy&amp;rdquo; things for a company that develops and hosts APIs for clients. These APIs are the backends to various services you&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard of or interacted with at some point in time. Because our clients depend on the performance and availability of our exposed services, monitoring is one of our top priorities. Without flexible, reliable, code-driven monitoring we&amp;rsquo;re setting ourselves up for failure.
Our monitoring platform of choice is Sensu, which is an absolutely fantastic piece of open source goodness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>haproxy consul template generation with docker registrator mesosphere and marathon</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/haproxy-consul-template-generation-with-docker-registrator-mesosphere-and-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 02:04:55 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/haproxy-consul-template-generation-with-docker-registrator-mesosphere-and-marathon/</guid>
      <description>Odds are if you&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled across this post it&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re running into the same issue I had: your docker-backed services are using the wrong IP in Consul-Template. Assuming your workflow looks like this:
 Commit code change CI server triggers a docker image build Image is pushed to registry and API call is made to Marathon to deploy application Marathon deploys the docker container with bridged networking, assigns it a random IP Registrator detects the new container and registers the service with Consul Consul template picks up the new container and should add another host to the HAProxy config Oh shit, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work :(  I&amp;rsquo;m guessing step 6 is where the wheels come off for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unifi wireless metrics with sensu</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/unifi-wireless-metrics-with-sensu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 03:51:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/unifi-wireless-metrics-with-sensu/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this exercise is to create a Metric for Sensu that&amp;rsquo;ll poll the Unifi controller and display the signal strength of connected wireless devices. This will allow me to get a visual of the type of connection devices in my house are getting as well as let me somewhat track the comings and goings of my devices.
Because no scripts like this currently exist for Unifi, I had to dig in and see what my options were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>installing sentry on ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/quick-start-installing-sentry-on-ubuntu-14-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 17:21:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/quick-start-installing-sentry-on-ubuntu-14-04/</guid>
      <description>Intro So you want to deploy Sentry in your local environment, eh? Assuming you already know what Sentry does, I&amp;rsquo;ll just give you the tagline from their website: Sentry provides real-time crash reporting for your web apps, mobile apps, and games. That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fantastic summary. What I use it for is gathering, grouping, and alerting on Ruby on Rails application issues. It wraps errors up in to a nice, easy to digest package that you can work through, resolve, and get trend analysis on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>install vmware vcenter 6 with less than 8gb ram</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/install-vmware-vcenter-6-with-less-than-8gb-ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 02:10:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/install-vmware-vcenter-6-with-less-than-8gb-ram/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the most frustrating thing about vCenter 6 is the hard 8GB of RAM requirement to simply install the application on a Windows server. To a lot of people, including myself, carving out 8GB of RAM VM in a home lab just to run vCenter for a host or two is a big ask.
But beyond that, even if you&amp;rsquo;re using a physical computer that has exactly 8GB of installed RAM, if any of that RAM goes to an integrated video card, and thus doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear available to Windows, you&amp;rsquo;ll be blocked from running the VCenter installer as your system will have slightly less than a full 8GB of RAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>homelab progress</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/homelab-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 14:25:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/homelab-progress/</guid>
      <description>A couple months ago I started building a homelab to assist in studying for the CCNA exam. I&amp;rsquo;m a pretty hands-on learner so having hardware that I can plug into and manipulate goes a long way. The home lab started out pretty modestly: 1x Cisco 3750 (WS-C3750-48TS-S), 1x Cisco 2980G XL, and 1x Cisco 2811 router. All of this was sitting on a 15U mini floor rack.
Over the course of the next few months I started adding components until it reached this point:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>issues resolving .local dns in ubuntu 15.04</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/issues-resolving-local-dns-in-ubuntu-15-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 14:25:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/issues-resolving-local-dns-in-ubuntu-15-04/</guid>
      <description>The problem After getting my Ubuntu 15.04 desktop setup I noticed Chrome/Firefox was unable to properly resolve my local domain (*.home.local).
For example, when trying to view the vCenter web interface at https://vc.home.local, or trying to SSH into my PostgreSQL development box postgres-dev-01.home.local I&amp;rsquo;d just get ssh: Could not resolve hostname exit: Temporary failure in name resolution. This was made especially odd since an nslookup was able to resolve everything just fine:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>recursive unrar script for windows</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/recursive-unrar-script-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 13:31:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/recursive-unrar-script-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>This script, as well as similar scripts can be found on the internet but I tend to keep losing the pages that have it. So for my own archival reasons, as well as making it a little easier for others to find, here it is.
This script uses winrar to recursively extract rar archives. This is very useful if you legally download seasons of shows and don&amp;rsquo;t want to extract each episode one by one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>disable gzip compression in fog</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/disable-gzip-compression-in-fog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 13:26:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/disable-gzip-compression-in-fog/</guid>
      <description>This was originally posted on my old blog back in 2010ish, restored it here for archival purposes.
Recently I changed the software the imaging server at work uses from Clonezilla to FOG. There were many reasons for the change such as a better web interface, image deployment queue, etc however one of the main things I was looking forward to was storage nodes which allows for distribution of images across multiple servers to extend storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post, woo!</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/first-post-woo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 16:30:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/first-post-woo/</guid>
      <description>To celebrate, have a cat</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
