<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on steves ramblings</title>
    <link>https://www.stevem.io/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on steves ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:30:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stevem.io/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>using rails 5 and paperclip s3 with minio</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/paperclip-s3-minio-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/paperclip-s3-minio-rails/</guid>
      <description>Odds are if you&amp;rsquo;ve landed here you&amp;rsquo;re aware of what Paperclip is and the purpose it servces within a Rails application. If not, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a gem that will handle file uploads. In my case I use it for resizing images, saving them somewhere (S3), then easily presenting them back to the user inside of a view.
Note: This tutorial should work with any S3 compatible object storage API. Minio is just one of the more common ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getting started with openshift v3 on vmware</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/getting-started-with-openshift-v3-on-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 07:23:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/getting-started-with-openshift-v3-on-vmware/</guid>
      <description>Goal After following this tutorial you should end up with a functional environment running OpenShift Origin. This environment will consist of 1 Master and 4 Nodes which isn&amp;rsquo;t a fully production-ready environment as ideally you will have multiple masters. We will be taking advantage of the OpenShift Ansible repository to tackle a majority of the heavy lifting, thus most of these steps fit into the &amp;ldquo;prep work&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;testing that everything worked as planned&amp;rdquo; category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing ASDM Login Error on Cisco ASA and ASAv</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/fixing-asdm-cisco-asa-and-asav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 11:03:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/fixing-asdm-cisco-asa-and-asav/</guid>
      <description>The problem &amp;ndash; ASDM Won&amp;rsquo;t launch properly When setting up a Cisco ASA Virtual Appliance (ASAv) in my lab I ran into issues getting ASDM to launch properly. When attempting to login I&amp;rsquo;d be prompted with the message &amp;ldquo;Unable to launch device manager from X.X.X.X&amp;rdquo; as seen in the screenshot below:
The logs indicate it&amp;rsquo;s an error with how SSL is configured on the ASA:
Application Logging Started at Thu Dec 15 15:51:05 CST 2016 --------------------------------------------- Local Launcher Version = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unifi wireless metrics with sensu</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/unifi-wireless-metrics-with-sensu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 03:51:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/unifi-wireless-metrics-with-sensu/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this exercise is to create a Metric for Sensu that&amp;rsquo;ll poll the Unifi controller and display the signal strength of connected wireless devices. This will allow me to get a visual of the type of connection devices in my house are getting as well as let me somewhat track the comings and goings of my devices.
Because no scripts like this currently exist for Unifi, I had to dig in and see what my options were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>installing sentry on ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/quick-start-installing-sentry-on-ubuntu-14-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 17:21:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/quick-start-installing-sentry-on-ubuntu-14-04/</guid>
      <description>Intro So you want to deploy Sentry in your local environment, eh? Assuming you already know what Sentry does, I&amp;rsquo;ll just give you the tagline from their website: Sentry provides real-time crash reporting for your web apps, mobile apps, and games. That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fantastic summary. What I use it for is gathering, grouping, and alerting on Ruby on Rails application issues. It wraps errors up in to a nice, easy to digest package that you can work through, resolve, and get trend analysis on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>install vmware vcenter 6 with less than 8gb ram</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/install-vmware-vcenter-6-with-less-than-8gb-ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 02:10:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/install-vmware-vcenter-6-with-less-than-8gb-ram/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps the most frustrating thing about vCenter 6 is the hard 8GB of RAM requirement to simply install the application on a Windows server. To a lot of people, including myself, carving out 8GB of RAM VM in a home lab just to run vCenter for a host or two is a big ask.
But beyond that, even if you&amp;rsquo;re using a physical computer that has exactly 8GB of installed RAM, if any of that RAM goes to an integrated video card, and thus doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear available to Windows, you&amp;rsquo;ll be blocked from running the VCenter installer as your system will have slightly less than a full 8GB of RAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>recursive unrar script for windows</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/recursive-unrar-script-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 13:31:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/recursive-unrar-script-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>This script, as well as similar scripts can be found on the internet but I tend to keep losing the pages that have it. So for my own archival reasons, as well as making it a little easier for others to find, here it is.
This script uses winrar to recursively extract rar archives. This is very useful if you legally download seasons of shows and don&amp;rsquo;t want to extract each episode one by one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>disable gzip compression in fog</title>
      <link>https://www.stevem.io/post/disable-gzip-compression-in-fog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 13:26:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stevem.io/post/disable-gzip-compression-in-fog/</guid>
      <description>This was originally posted on my old blog back in 2010ish, restored it here for archival purposes.
Recently I changed the software the imaging server at work uses from Clonezilla to FOG. There were many reasons for the change such as a better web interface, image deployment queue, etc however one of the main things I was looking forward to was storage nodes which allows for distribution of images across multiple servers to extend storage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
